Arise for Social Justice Records, 1956-2010 (bulk 1985-2010)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION
  - Events
    - Clothing Giveaway, 199-91 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Council of Churches Mothers Fund Family Outings 1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Eastern States Exposition bus trip 1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Family Day at Coney Island 1988 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Recognition Dinner 2005-06 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Reference file 1989, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Publications
    - Buttons "to be done" undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Graphics undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Poetry undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Membership Memo/Memo 1994-2000 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Newsletter
      - 1988 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Our Voices Heard 1990-95 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - 2002-10 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Surviving Together 2003 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Taking it to the Streets 2005-06 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Unidentified undated pages (Box 4, Folder 42A)
    - Arizine, [see SERIES X. HIV/AIDS PREVENTION AND EDUCATION]
    - Words of the People [creative writing group] undated (Box 4, Folder 42B)
    - The Voice 2002, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Resources
    - Brochures and lists for referrals 1993-2005, undated (Box 4, Folder 44-45)
    - Songs, poems, cartoons, and inspirational quotes 1993-2003, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Statistics 1980-97, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
- SERIES II. FINANCIAL MATERIALS
  - Arise Fiscal Committee 1987-2003, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Arise Loan Fund 2003-2004, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Bookkeeping 1988-2004, undated (Box 4, Folder 50-52)
  - Budget 1988-2005, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Financial statements 1987-2006, undated (Box 4, Folder 54-55)
  - Fundraising
    - General 1993-2003, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Plan 2004-05 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Arise Fundraising Committee 1986-93, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Arise Resource Development Committee 1993-2004, undated (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Appeal letters
      - General 1989-2010, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - May 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Organizers' training 1999 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Marsha's Apartment 2004-05 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Corporate Giving program undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Events
      - Miscellaneous 1987-2005, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Block Party Aug 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Cheap Chic Fashion Show May 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Raffle 1987, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
      - Spring Fling/BYOB Dance 1988-89 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Grants
      - General 1993-2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Grantwriting 1991-2004, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Proposals and reports
        - General support
          - Miscellaneous 1994-97, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
          - Anonymous donor 2000-01 (Box 5, Folder 20)
          - Haymarket People's Fund 1986, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
          - Norman Foundation 1992-94 (Box 5, Folder 23)
          - Springfield Action Commission 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
        - Archives of Poor People's History, Skaggs Foundation 1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
        - Be a Father to Your Child Workshops, Springfield Infant Mortality and Teenage Pregnancy Coalition 1992 (Box 5, Folder 26)
        - Criminal Justice/Community Justice
          - Community Justice, Campaign for Human Development 1997-98 (Box 5, Folder 27)
          - Community Policing, Resist circa 1998 (Box 5, Folder 28)
          - Criminal Justice Project
            - Community Foundation of Western Massachusetts 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
            - Gardiner Howland Shaw Foundation 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
          - Criminal Justice Committee development, Haymarket People's Fund 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
          - Know Your Rights Project, Campaign for Human Development 1997 (Box 5, Folder 32)
          - Restorative Justice is Smart on Crime, Gardiner Howland Shaw Foundation 2004 (Box 5, Folder 33)
          - SpY 4 Justice (Springfield Youth for Justice), to unknown grantmaker 1994 (Box 5, Folder 34)
        - Department of Social Services system change organizing proposal to Campaign for Human Development (Box 5, Folder 35)
        - Economic Human Rights Project, to various grantmakers 1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
        - Empowerment
          - Empowerment Workshops, Discount Foundation 1992 (Box 5, Folder 37)
          - Empowerment Workshops for Low-Income Women
            - Agnes Lindsay Trust 1993 (Box 5, Folder 38)
            - Family Community Leadership Mini-Grant 1992 (Box 5, Folder 39)
          - Teenage Empowerment Workshop Series, Springfield Infant Mortality and Teenage Pregnancy Coalition 1991 (Box 5, Folder 40)
        - Family Support, Education, and Advocacy, W.K. Kellogg Foundation 1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
        - Food Coop 1996 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        - Health Insurance Access Campaign
          - Miscellaneous undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
          - Ben and Jerry's Foundation 1993 (Box 5, Folder 44)
          - Families U.S.A. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 45)
          - Haymarket People's Fund 1993 (Box 5, Folder 46)
          - Public Welfare Foundation 1992 (Box 5, Folder 47)
          - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation 1992 (Box 5, Folder 48)
        - Hot Meals Program, United Way 1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
        - Housing/Homelessness
          - Various projects, Fund for the Hungry and Homeless 1988-93 (Box 5, Folder 50)
          - Eviction Prevention Program, United Way of Pioneer Valley undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
          - Mason Square Neighborhood Community Land Trust, generic proposal undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
          - Neighborhood Community Land Trust Project, Discount Foundation 1993 (Box 5, Folder 53)
          - Single Room Occupancy (SRO) Housing (with Service Providers, Inc.)
            - Institute for Community Economics Revolving Loan Fund undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
            - Massachusetts Executive Office of Communities and Development, Community Services Block Grant (CSBG) 1985-98 (Box 5, Folder 55)
            - Public Welfare Foundation undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
          - Single Room Occupancy (SRO) Tenants' Union Organizing, Discount Foundation 1993 (Box 5, Folder 57)
          - Springfield Initiative (with Open Pantry Community Services), unidentified U.S. Government program 1994 (Box 5, Folder 58)
          - Transitional Housing for One Parent Families Project, United Way of Pioneer Valley 1987 (Box 5, Folder 59)
          - Winter Overflow Shelter emergency funding, Haymarket People's Fund 1992 (Box 5, Folder 60)
        - Myles Horton Free School, Peace Development Fund 1996 (Box 5, Folder 61)
        - Neighborhood Freedom Choir, to unknown grantmaker undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
        - New England People's Economic Summit
          - Haymarket People's Fund 1996-99 (Box 5, Folder 63)
          - Lawson Valentine Foundation 1996 (Box 5, Folder 64)
        - People Living with AIDS Consumer Group, unknown undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
        - People's Quincentenary Celebration, Warren Plaut Memorial Fund 1992 (Box 5, Folder 66)
        - Political Reform/Voter Education
          - Organizers' Training Project, Xeric Foundation 1999 (Box 5, Folder 67)
          - Political Reform in Springfield, Ford Foundation 1994 (Box 5, Folder 68)
          - Voter Education Committee, Piper Fund 1999 (Box 5, Folder 69)
          - Ward Representation Campaign, Community Training and Assistance Center undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
        - Self-Reliance Center
          - To various grantmakers 1992-94, undated (Box 5, Folder 71)
          - Frank Stanley Beveridge Foundation 1992 (Box 5, Folder 72)
        - Solidarity
          - Miscellaneous 1992 (Box 5, Folder 73)
          - U.S. Nicaragua Low-Income Links Project, Tides Foundation 1995 (Box 5, Folder 74)
        - Truth Squad Speakers' Bureau, to various grantmakers 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 75)
        - Volunteer Coordinator, Mott Foundation 1987 (Box 5, Folder 76)
        - Welfare
          - Miscellaneous 1985, 1997, undated (Box 5, Folder 77)
          - Economic Survival Coaltion (with Women's Alliance), unspecified 1997-99 (Box 5, Folder 78)
          - Welfare Rights Organizing Project, Peace Development Fund 1995-96 (Box 5, Folder 79)
        - Working Massachusetts, Western Massachusetts Chapter establishment, Catholic Campaign for Human Development 1999 (Box 5, Folder 80)
        - Youth Conference, various 1997 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Reference files
      - General 1989-2004, undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Foundation/Fund research 1985-2004, undated (Box 5, Folder 83-86)
    - Workshops 1993 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Miscellaneous 1995-2003, undated (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Reports 1989-93 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Taxes 1988-2005, undated (Box 5, Folder 90-91)
  - Tax exemption certificates 1987, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 92)
- SERIES III. CHILDREN AND YOUTH, [see also SERIES IV. CRIMINAL JUSTICE, SERIES IX. HEALTH CARE, and the restricted materials]
  - Department of Social Services (DSS) Advocacy? Reform?
    - General 1986-99, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Clippings 1986-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Arise Justice for Parents and Children Under DSS Advisory Board 1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Arise DSS Committee 1991-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Arise DSS Support Group
      - General 1992-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Meeting notes 1992-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 6-9)
    - [Arise] Children and Parents' Advocates (CAPA) 1993-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Play and rally "State of Destruction" 16 Jul 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Training materials and fact sheets undated (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - The Kids in Arise [group for children] 1989, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Arise Youth Group
    - General 1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Conference, "Be a Father to Your Child," 1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Legislation
    - General 1992-93, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - ACE (Affordable Childcare for Everyone) Bill 1993-98, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - H4247 (Child Abuse) 1997-98 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Organizations
    - Alliance for the Rights of Children (ARCH) 1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Massachusetts Department of Social Services
      - Area 4 Advisory Board 1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Forms and regulations 1983-98, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Family Law Task Force, Massachusetts Law Reform Institute 1994 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Single Parent Interactive Network (SPIN) 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Special Committee on Family Support and the Child Welfare System 1992-95, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Springfield Infant Mortality and Teen Pregnancy Prevention Coalition 1985-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Summer Youth Employment and Training Program (SYETP), New England Farmworkers Council 1990-99, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Subject files
    - General and miscellaneous 1984-97, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Adoption/Foster care 1986-2003, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Child abuse and neglect 1992-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Child abuse and child psychiatry 1979-95, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Child care and Day care 1985-97, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Child custody 1987-98 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Child support 1988-95 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Children and poverty 1990-98 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Gangs undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Parenting 1991-95, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Teenage pregnancy undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
- SERIES IV. CRIMINAL JUSTICE, [see also SERIES II. FINANCIAL MATERIALS and SERIES XXIII. VIOLENCE]
  - Arise Criminal Justice Committee
    - General 1992-96, undated (Box 6, Folder 39-42)
    - Campaign for a Responsible Police Commission 1995 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Community Service 1988-94, undated, [see also Restricted materials] (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Criminal Justice Project grant 1993-95 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Know Your Rights Project
      - General 1994-98, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Criminal Justice Advocacy Training Oct 1994 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - Pamphlet 1994 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Lawsuit, Officer Robert McFarlin vs. Arise 1995 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Police Complaint Advocacy Training 1997 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Criminal Justice Survey undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Arise Community Justice Committee
    - General 1996-99, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Community Justice Survey 1998 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Alternatives to Incarceration petition undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Crime
    - General 1992-98, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Crime bills 1993-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Victims/Survivors 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Criminal Justice System
    - General 1990-2004, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - American Friends Service Committee Criminal Justice Program 1992-2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Political prisoners 1992-2003, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sentencing/mandatory minimums 1993-2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Criminal Offender Record Information (CORI) 1990, 2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Death penalty
    - General 1977-2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Judge Albert Sabo, Pennsylvania 1997-98 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Massachusetts legislative hearing 1 Jul 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous cases 1993-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Mumia Abu-Jamal case 1994-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    - Organizations
      - Coalition Against Violence and the Death Penalty (CAVDP) 2001, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Equal Justice USA 1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Massachusetts Coalition Against the Death Penalty 1991-2001, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - National Coalition Against the Death Penalty 1994-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Massachusetts Justice Network 1992-94 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Police--General
    - Abuse/violence
      - General 1991-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Coalition Against Police Abuse (CAPA), Los Angeles 1993-95 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - "Fighting Police Abuse: A Community Action Manual," ACLU 1992 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Civilian review of police: general 1991-95 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Association for Civilian Oversight of Law Enforcement, national and international (NACOLE, IACOLE) 1994-95, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - National Coalition on Police Accountability (N-COPA) 1995-96 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Police-Springfield and Pioneer Valley
    - General 1993-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Brutality/violence 1996-2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Chief selection process 1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Citizens' complaints 1995-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Citizen Review Board 1992-95, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Community Policing
      - General 1993-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Citizens for Effective Community Policing (CECP) 1994-95, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Fryar, Charles case 1993-95, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Police-Community relations 1992-97, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Octagon Lounge incident 1965-95, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - October 22 Coalition, National Day of Protest Against Police Brutality 1998 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Quinn Bill and attack on City Councilor Morris Jones 1990-94 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Rally following Rodney King verdict 1992-93, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Report, "Policing Springfield," 1993 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Schoolfield, Benjamin shooting
      - General 1993-99, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Party for officer Don Brown 1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Springfield Dialogue 1994-95 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Prisons and jails
    - General
      - National 1994-2001, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Massachusetts 1990-2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Campaign to Stop Construction of the Chicopee Women's Prison, Springfield Harm Reduction Coalition (ShaRC) 2003-2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Class Action lawsuit vs. NYNEX 1994-95 (Box 7, Folder 41-42)
    - Health care 1994, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Interfaith Prison Pilgrimage 1997-2000 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Massachusetts Department of Corrections policies 1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Prison Awareness Week 1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Prison Connections newsletter 1996-98 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Private prisons 1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Too Many Americans in Prison Summit April 1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Women/mothers in criminal justice system
    - General 1992-2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - YWCA Female Offender Program undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Youth violence
    - General 1988-97, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Gangs
      - General 1992-94, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Community in Support of the Gang Truce, Los Angeles undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Springfield 1994-95, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Youth curfew, Springfield 1995-96 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- SERIES V. EDUCATION AND TRAINING
  - Arise
    - General training manual 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Board training 1986-2003 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Workshops and presentations
      - General and miscellaneous 1988-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Advocacy 1992, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Basic Maintenance 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Basic Secretarial Skills 1993-94, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Building Church Relationships 1998, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Civil disobedience 1998, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Coalitions undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Community Organizing 1973-96, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Conflict Resolution undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Credit Counseling 1985, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Diversity undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Doorknocking and Outreach undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Empowerment 1989-93, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Leadership 1982, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Lobbying 1985, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Media 2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Meetings 1984, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Organization Development undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Outreach undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Petitioning undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Political Education 1992, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Positive Thinking Seminar 1987 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Root Cause Training 1999 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Self motivation 1987 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Stress undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Myles Horton Free School 1994, 1997-2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 37-39)
    - Writing Group 1992, 2005, undated, [see also Publications in SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION] (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Other organizations
    - Center for Popular Economics 1986-96, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Community Training and Assistance Center (CTAC) undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Family Community Leadership Training Institute 1991-92 (Box 8, Folder 43-44)
    - Massachusetts Law Reform Institute (MLRI), Challenge and Change: Legal Services in the '90s series undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - New World Theatre Arts Partners Project 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Organizing and Leadership Training Center (OLTC) 1986-87, undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Western Massachusetts Regional Popular Educators 2000 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Reference files
    - Education, general and miscellaneous 1988-98, undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Consumer education 1987-97, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Massachusetts Comprehensive Assessment System (MCAS) 1999-2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - New England Education Loan Marketing Association (Nellie Mae) 1997-98, undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Popular and people's education 2001-02, undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Springfield and area schools 1992-2003, undated (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Training resources, miscellaneous 1988-99, undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
- SERIES VI. ELDERLY
  - General 1976-96, undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Health care
    - General 1983-93, undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Visiting Nurse Association (VNA) undated (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Organizations
    - General 1989-91, undated (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Gray Panthers 1979-93, undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Massachusetts Senior Action Council 1988-93 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Social Security 1983-98, undated (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Volunteering 1993-2006, undated (Box 8, Folder 63)
- SERIES VII. ENVIRONMENT AND SOCIAL JUSTICE
  - General 1985-2006, undated (Box 8, Folder 64-65)
  - Arise undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Economic Sustainability 1992-93, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Healthy Schools Network 1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Save James Bay 1991-92 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Toxics Action Center 1996-98, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- SERIES VIII. FOOD/HUNGER, [see also Restricted materials]
  - Arise Community Garden Project 1994, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Arise Food Coop, [see also grant proposals in SERIES II. FINANCIAL MATERIALS]
    - General 1989-98, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Committee 1996-97, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Brochures 1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Northeast Cooperatives 1995-98, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Reference file re: cooperatives 1993-96, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Arise Hot Meals Program 1987-89, undated
    [see also SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS]
    - General 1983-92, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Financial 1987-89, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Menus 1987-89, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Worksheets 1987-88, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Food/hunger: general 1983-96, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Food and nutrition fact sheets 1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Food Banks 1988-2004, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Food For All 1990-95, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Food Research and Action Center (FRAC)
    - General 1989-97, undated (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
    - Campaign to End Childhood Hunger 1991-92 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Community Childhood Hunger Identification Project: A Survey of Childhood Hunger in the United States 1995 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Foodlines newsletter 1988-93 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Food Stamps, [see also SERIES XXIV. WELFARE]
    - General 1988-97, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Advocacy and training 1997 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Massachusetts Law Reform Institute, Basic Benefits Training: Food Stamps 1993 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Project Bread Food Stamps Hotline 1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Hunger in Massachusetts 1987-91, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Massachusetts Anti-Hunger Coalition
    - General 1988-89 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Training, Springfield 1989 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Massachusetts Nutrition Board 1989 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Medford Declaration to End Hunger in the U.S. 1989-92, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Open Pantry Community Services 1987-97, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture
    - Summer Food Service Programs 1987-92 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) Program
      - General 1985, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Center on Budget and Policy Priorities
        - General 1992-92 (Box 9, Folder 36)
        - The WIC Project 1993 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- SERIES IX. HEALTH CARE
  - Arise Health Care Committee
    - General 1985-97, undated (Box 9, Folder 38-42)
    - Notebook Sep-Dec 1996 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Arise Member Health Care Questionnaire 1994 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Health Care Access Information Line 1995, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Health Care/Health Insurance Access Questionnaire circa 1993 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Neighborhood Health Center, Mason Square 1993-95, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Telephone poll of Medicaid providers 1990 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Wellness groups 1987-94, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)